A Guide to the Papers of John F. Banks, 1910-1959
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
John F. Banks Papers, 1910-1959
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1985-34
The Banks Papers consist of photographs and artifacts from the Christiansburg Institute. Acc. #1985-34
John F. Banks
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mr. John F. Banks became principal of the Christiansburg Industrial Institute in 1949. Banks was a graduate of Wilberforce University in Ohio and Hampton Institute. During his tenure the United States Supreme Court ruled that school segregation based on color was unconstitutional. Nevertheless, it was not until the 1960's when Montgomery County began efforts to dismantle their dual system of education. Mr. Banks was the last principal of Christiansburg. The school closed in 1966.
Other material about Christiansburg may be found in: The Amanda DeHart Papers Acc. # 1988-61, The Christiansburg Alumni Association Papers Acc. # 1988-62, The Virginia Inter-Scholastic Association Papers Acc. # 1969-37, and The Virginia Teacher Association Papers Acc. # 1969-14, all located at Virginia State University.
Scope and Content Information
Official records and photographs documenting some of the programs and activities at the Christiansburg Industrial Institute.
Series Description
Series I. Printed Catalogs and bulletins of the Christiansburg Industrial Institution
Series II. Photographs Photographs showing programs, buildings, and activities at Christiansburg
Series III. Artifacts Christiansburg Seal
Contents List
- Printed
  - The Twenty First Annual Catalogue: The Christianburg Industrial Institute 1916-1917 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - The Christianburg Institute Bulletin 1942-1943 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Photographs
  - Baseball Team- Virginia State College For Negroes 1930-1946 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Boy Scouts (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Cheerleader 1907 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - A Class (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Class Scene- Basketball (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Class Scene- Frech (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Class Scene - Gymnastics (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Christianburg House (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Football (Box-folder 1:11)
  - A Girls Gardening Class 1930-1946 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Home Economics- Cosmetology (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Home Economics - Cooking (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Home Economics- Sewing (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Majorette (Box-folder 1:16)
  - School Club (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Students Harvesting Wheat (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Student Scene ( A Performance) (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Bailey- Norris Hall (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Christian Colored Hospital (Box-folder 1:21)
  - C.I.I- Overview (Birds Eye View) (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Farm Scene (Boys Spraying Fruit Trees) (Box-folder 1:23)
  - "Girls" Sitting Room (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Industrial Building (New) (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Morris Hall (Male Dorm) (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Principal's Home (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Science Lab (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Shop- Carpeting (Box-folder 1:29)
  - Students Plowing (Box-folder 1:30)
- Artifact
  - The Christianburg Seal constructed of wood